Tatyana Ludanik

place of birth: Moscow, Russia date of birth: 17.02.1985 nationality: Russian family status: not married city: Moscow

phone: +7 925 785 22 21 website: www.ludanik.com



EDUCATION

2014 – 2016	Theatre design, The British High School of Art and Design, Moscow
2006 – 2011	Graphic Design, Moscow Art and Industry Institute, Moscow
2005 – 2006	Interior Design, Russia National Institute of Design, Moscow
2002 – 2006	Economics, Russia Lomonosov Moscow State University

WORK EXPERIENCE

since 2018	Artist
2016 – 2018	Artist. Gorky Park, Moscow
2015 – 2016	Art Director and curator of contemporary dance and theatre. DK Trehgorka, Moscow
2014 – 2014	Art Director. Mosgorpark, Moscow
2006 – 2014	Art Director and designer of Moscow leading publishing houses and marketing agencies

BIOGRAPHY

Tatyana Ludanik studied graphic design at Moscow Art and Industry Institute, where she acquired the necessary toolkit of skills to visualize her ideas. Further studies of theatre design at the British High School of Art and Design provided Tatyana with deeper understanding of post dramatic theatre and immersive art, these insights inspire her to create works that stimulate sensory experiences of a viewer. In her artistic career Tatyana also functions as a manager and producer of her own projects, the roles that she had been prepared for while studying Economics as her Bachelor's degree at Lomonosov Moscow State University.

Tatyana works in different media. The scale and scope of her projects vary from large-size public art objects in city central parks, installations, video art to costume performances and set design. The geography of her recent projects is impressive – Tatyana has created public art in Gorky Park, installations for permanent collection of Slava Polunin (Le Moulin Jaune, France), Skolkovo Industrial Park (Moscow, Russia) and The German Embassy (Goethe-Institut, Russia). She produced a number of interactive installations for ARMA, costume performances for New Holland, Gorky Park, Aviapark, etc. As a set designer, Tatyana collaborated with international festival in Norway (Barents Spektakel 2019, Kirkenes) and Russia (Yuri Bashmet International Art Festival, Sochi 2019, 2020).

Currently, Tatyana resides and creates in Moscow, the city where she was born and bred.

ARTIST STATEMENT

Working in various media, from public art, installations, video art to costume performances, I always strive to create a deeply immersive environment for my viewers. As in post-dramatic theatre, where there is no barrier between the action and the audience, hence no place for passive observation, I invite my audience to take on active roles and become participants. They let Art inside through their sensory experiences. And this is just the point of entry, Art continues in my viewers as they keep it in their feelings, emotions, perceptions and they take it with them beyond the walls of a theatre or the performance location. This is what motivates me and feeds my curiosity – art as an everyday experience and experiment.

That's why I enjoy working with city parks, open public spaces, urban landscapes, where I can transform the familiar daily routine. I am deeply convinced that space is an organic extension of us, humans, and as we have an impact on the space around us, so we in our turn can be transformed by space, through immediate reactions and interactions. I believe, that the inner child inside every one of us is still eager for new sensations, fresh emotions and bold adventures. We can travel back to our childhood bliss differently – some people immerse in virtual reality, some exercise spiritual practices, others try to expand their minds with various agents. As for me, Art is a powerful psychedelic medium that can transform our reality and save the inner child from the boredom and fatigue of the everyday life.

New technologies enable us to immerse deeper in VR, however, I prefer to extend not virtual, but the real world. Therefore, in my works I use organic and authentic materials, everyday objects and images (soil, wood, metals, liquids, clothes, etc.). Building on their deep mythological and symbolic meaning, I place them in a totally different context, exposing them to new perspective and perception. I invest a lot of time in experiments with materials, studying their properties and capabilities, mixing techniques in order to find the right technology for the right outcome. Every time I seek to create art, which integrity and truth are those of a living organism. Only such reality can win your trust and acceptance, only such art can immerse you and turn an outside observer into its active participant.

COLLABORATIONS

2020	The German Embassy, Moscow
2020, 2019	Winter International Arts Festival, Sochi
2020, 2019	Mutabor, Moscow
2020-2018	Aviapark, Moscow
2019	Barents Spektakel, Kirkiness, Norway
2019, 2018	New Holland,St. Petersburg
2018-2016	Gorky Park, Moscow
2016, 2015	Slava Polunin, Le Moulin Jaune, France
2016	Skolkovo, Moscow
2015	Outline, Moscow

RESIDENCY

- 2015 'Teach a pigeon to fly', Le Moulin Jaune of Slava Polunin, France
- 2016 'Picnic as an art'. Le Moulin Jaune of Slava Polunin, France

2016 A kinetic sculpture 'Izo Rhythm'. Skolkovo, Moscow (in a permanent collection). December Size: 2.5 metre high

- 2016 Installation 'Frozen Fountain'.Gorky Park,
 Moscow. 17 November 2016–10 March 2017
 Size: 25 x 9 metre
- 2015 Installation 'Stairways to the Sky'. Moulin Jaune of Slava Polunin, France (in a permanent collection).
 April
 Size: composition of 6 stair chairs 3.8 metre to 5 metre
- 2015 Interactive installation 'Have A Nice Trip'. Outline,Moscow. 4–5 JulySize: Composition of 5 baths
- 2015 Installation 'Arche' (The Rite of Spring by Stravinsky). Boyarski palaty, Moscow 9–12 May Size: Composition of 8 textile shirts 3-metre high

PUBLIC PROJECTS

- A light-dynamic audio installation 'The Pyramid'.
 Gorky Park, Moscow. November 2020–March 2021
 Size: 15 metres high and 21,5 metres in diagonal
- 2020 Installation 'The Berlin Wall Crack' for the 30th anniversary of the reunification of Germany. Muzeon, then the Goethe-Institute, Moscow. 10 October Size: 2.8 x 3.6 metre
- 2020 A light-dynamic audio installation 'Dance Floor's Heart'. Mutabor, Moscow. 8 February Size: 1.3 metre
- 2019 Video art 'Cell'. Mutabor, Moscow. 2 November Size: 2.5 x 2.5 metre
- 2018 Musical installation-performance 'The Moon'.
 Gorky Park, Moscow,
 31 August 2 September
 Size: 6 metre Moon on 127 x 54 metre pond
- 2017 A light-dynamic audio installation 'StereoHeart' (Matrix). Gorky Park, Moscow
 17 November 2017–10 March 2018
 Size: 10 x 10 metre, external rhombus located within a 60 x 60 metre fountain basin

COSTUMES & PERFORMANCES:

- 2021 Performance 'Arche' (version 2021) Mutabor, Moscow. 27 March
- 2021 Performance 'Shiny Ladies' Aviapark, Moscow. 8 March
- 2020 Performance 'Sweet Couple'.Aviapark, Moscow. 14 February
- 2019 Performance 'Ms. BlueHand'. Aviapark, Moscow. 5 July
- 2019 Performance 'The Cloud Women'.
 Aviapark, Moscow. 8 March
- 2018 Performance 'BodyParts'.New Holland Island, Saint Petersburg.November 2018–March 2019
- 2018 Performance 'Puzany'.

 Gorky Park, Moscow. 16–17 February
- 2017 Performance 'Stereo Types'.Gorky Park, Moscow. 17 November
- 2017 Performance 'Monster Hugs'.
 Gorky Park, Moscow. 25–26 February